Fabian Gunzinger

fabiangunzinger.github.io fa.gunzinger@gmail.com in fabiangunzinger O fabiangunzinger

I'm a behavioural scientist with 10+ years of research and 5+ years of project management experience in academia, central banking, and consulting. I'm happiest when solving computational problems and writing beautiful code to study human behaviour using large scale datasets and methods from data science and econometrics. The academic in me loves doing this to better understand how people form habits and manage their money; the craftsman in me, to help build great products.

Education

PhD in Behavioural Science, Warwick Business School, 2019–2022 (expected)
MPhil in Economics, University of Oxford, 2015–2017
MSc in Economics, University of Bern, 2012–2014
BSc in Economics, University of Bern, 2009–2012

Pre-university: commercial apprenticeship, military service, applied business studies, 2001–2009

Work experience

Data scientist, tracktheeconomy.ac.uk, December 2020-June 2021

- Designing and building interactive dashboard to track UK economic performance in real time at local level
- Working with private data providers to build fully automated pre-processing pipeline integrating all data assets such as individual-level bank-statement, mobile location data, and credit-scores (all of GB/TB-order size)
- Learning R and Shiny from scratch, and setting up and managing AWS resources (IAM, S3, EC2)

Research Advisor, Behavioural Insights Team, London, October 2018-December 2019

- Designing, implementing, and analysing large-scale randomised controlled trials across a range of policy areas including one trial in 300+ schools with 10,000+ students across the UK
- Conducting exploratory data analysis including one to identify extraneous calls to a major UK police force
- Training and mentoring colleagues in Stata programming and statistical methods

Research assistant, Department of Economics, Oxford University, September-December 2017

- Performing analysis of a large-scale randomised controlled trial in Kenya testing the effect of behavioural interventions
- Setting up code-sharing platform for the lab on GitHub and training colleagues to use it

Economist and staff to the Vice-Chairman, Swiss National Bank, Bern and Zurich, April 2013–April 2015 Research scientist, Center for Health, Policy and Economics, University of Lucerne, Fall 2014 and 2015

- · Conducting data analysis for a project on the causal link between socioeconomic status and health behaviour
- Developing code for visualisations using ggplot2 that was used by the rest of the team

Intern, Credit Suisse Global Financial Market Research, Zurich, March-June 2012

Research assistant, Chair of Applied Macroeconomics, ETH Zurich, September 2009–May 2013

Skills

Programming languages: Python, R, Stata, SQL

Tools: AWS, bash, Git, LATEX, Make

Languages: German (native), English (fluent), French (basic)

Teaching

Big Data Analytics, Warwick Business School, Teaching assistant to Neil Stewart, Spring 2021

• Introduction to R (using R for Data Science) and machine learning (using An Introduction to Statistical Learning)

Private tutor, teaching econometrics and microeconomic theory to MBA, graduate, and undergraduate students, 2015-2020

Research

Levelling Down and the COVID-19 Lockdowns: Uneven Regional Recovery in UK Consumer Spending

(with John Gathergood, Benedict Guttman-Kenney, Edika Quispe-Torreblanca and Neil Stewart) *CEPR Covid Economics*, 2021, vol. 67, pp. 24-52.

It's Politics, Stupid! Political Constraints Explain Government's Reactions to the Great Recession

(with Jan-Egbert Sturm)

Fiscal Politics. Edited by Vitor Gaspar, Sanjeev Gupta, and Carlos Mulas-Granados. International Monetary Fund, 2017, p. 177-213. (Reprint of paper below.)

It's Politics, Stupid! Political Constraints Explain Government's Reactions to the Great Recession

(with Jan-Egbert Sturm, the paper is a version of my undergraduate thesis) Kyklos, 2016, vol. 69(4), pp. 557-636.

Awards and honours

Warwick Business School PhD scholarship (full funding for 4 years)

Berrow Scholarship, Lincoln College, University of Oxford (full funding for MPhil degree)

Faculty Prize for graduating with highest honours (top 5 %) from MSc in Economics, University of Bern

Participant of the 11. Carroll Round (selective undergraduate conference), Georgetown University, Washington D.C., 2012